<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on myl3z.me - CyberSec - Dev - Server</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on myl3z.me - CyberSec - Dev - Server</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de-de</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 11:05:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myl3z.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Is Raid</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/what-is-raid/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 11:05:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/what-is-raid/</guid><description>What is RAID? RAID stands for Redundant Array of Independent Disks. And as the name says, it&amp;rsquo;s about using multiple drives in combination. The goal is often to have more speed, more reliability or even both.
RAID Level There are different possibilities for the combination in a RAID system. They called RAID level for different purposes.
RAID-0 Also called Stripping. It combines two or more drives into one big space. The data is distributed over the drives.</description></item><item><title>What Is Journald</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/what-is-journald/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:06:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/what-is-journald/</guid><description>What is journald? It&amp;rsquo;s a logging framework from systemd. You can use it with journalctl. If you just use journalctl without paramters you will get an excerpt of all logs.
-f You can follow the new logs that are incoming using the -f parameters: journalctl -f. It&amp;rsquo;s like tail -f for files.
&amp;ndash;since To filter the logs you can use parameters like --since. Example: journalctl --since=&amp;quot;2020-01-01&amp;quot; then it will give you the logs that exists since that date.</description></item><item><title>Part 2 What Is Systemd</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/part-2-what-is-systemd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:46:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/part-2-what-is-systemd/</guid><description>Part 2 - What is systemd? I already know what systemd is and what is does. But I want to learn more about the configuration options it have or get a better understanding of the file, which I created for the service.
There are a lot more keywords that can be used in that file to make systemd do other things.
Options There are a lot options. In the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading, there are listed the following options as the common ones that will cross your way regarding service untis:</description></item><item><title>Part 1 - What Is Systemd</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/part-1-what-is-systemd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 22:42:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/part-1-what-is-systemd/</guid><description>What is systemd? systemd is a deamon which handles the steps after the kernel is loaded with it&amp;rsquo;s important modules.
So you can say it&amp;rsquo;s an initialization system. That&amp;rsquo;s another definition I found in the internet.
Units systemd is managed by units. There are different types of units:
Service Units Socket Units Target Units Device Units Mount Units Automount Units Snapshot Units Timer Units Swap Units Path Units Slice Units Scope Units I think the most interesting for me are the Service Units.</description></item><item><title>03 - 18 min - Initial Ramdisk</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/03-18-min-initial-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:25:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/03-18-min-initial-ramdisk/</guid><description>initrd Today&amp;rsquo;s topic is about initrd - the Initial Ramdisk.
We&amp;rsquo;re still in the boot process. As I understand, the initial ramdisk contains all needed drivers and module to start the computer, before the computer has access to all drives.
The initrd is loaded by the bootloader, in our case it&amp;rsquo;s GRUB2. Usually the initial ramdisk is created in the installation process of the operating system, so it consists everything it needs to start the computer properly.</description></item><item><title>02 - 18 min - Grub 2</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-18-min-grub-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-18-min-grub-2/</guid><description>GRUB 2 Todays topic was GRUB and bootloader. Of course I won&amp;rsquo;t get to much into the deep, but just to read some of the explanations at least help me to understand it more.
What is GRUB? It stands for Grand Unified Bootloader and the current major version is 2.
Bootloader What is a bootloader? It&amp;rsquo;s basically a program that loads the operating system. After the BIOS make it&amp;rsquo;s system checks the hard drives are red and the first part of the hard drive stores the bootloader.</description></item><item><title>01 - 18 min - Server Configuration</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-18-min-server-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:08:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-18-min-server-configuration/</guid><description>18 min per Day What are the Rules? Every Day - 18 minutes - for one year.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how far this can get. In the meantime I will try to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
Either just small updates or more content for topics I find interesting.
Server configuration I have two big books about server configuration. One is for linux and one for Windows. I will start with the linux book.</description></item><item><title>03 - Hacking Lab - Scanning the network</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/03-hacking-lab-scanning-the-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:11:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/03-hacking-lab-scanning-the-network/</guid><description>Scanning the network Note: Before going into the fun stuff. Good news! I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed the internet connection problem, by using IP addresses that can communicate. Somehow 192.168.2.1 and 192.168.25.1 can&amp;rsquo;t communicate, even if I&amp;rsquo;m using 255.255.0.0 as a subnet mask. That means that the network is really big now. If you would like to learn more about networking and subnetting, leave me a comment :)
Update the VMs To have fun with the fun stuff, I want to add some configurations to my domain controller.</description></item><item><title>02 - Hacking Lab - Installing the Vms</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-hacking-lab-installing-the-vms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:11:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-hacking-lab-installing-the-vms/</guid><description>Installation Installing Promox was quite easy. Download, copy with balenaEtcher and boot from the flash drive. Click, Click, Click, Done.
Following the mini plan I&amp;rsquo;ve made, I&amp;rsquo;m starting with the installation of the VMs. Downloading Windows for Evaluation. I need Windows Server 2022, which will run the Domain Controller. And for every Workstation I will use Windows 11 Enterprise, since it&amp;rsquo;s also available for Evaluation in the Evaluation Center.
The first problem occured: I can&amp;rsquo;t start the freshly created machines, because something with Virtualization and my mainboard needs to be configured.</description></item><item><title>01 - Hacking Lab - The idea</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-hacking-lab-the-idea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:51:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-hacking-lab-the-idea/</guid><description>Welcome Hi! Hello! Welcome!
My name is xander and I like cyber security, software development and servers.
This blog will be my personal blog about cyber security, software development and servers.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see!
Leave me a comment if you have questions or just want to say hi.
First project: Hacking Lab What is a hacking lab?
It&amp;rsquo;s basically a playground for my cyber security stuff. To get a better understand I want to build my own infrastructure and then attack it.</description></item></channel></rss>