<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on myl3z.me - CyberSec - Dev - Server</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on myl3z.me - CyberSec - Dev - Server</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>de-de</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:26:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://myl3z.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>02 18 Min Grub 2</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-18-min-grub-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-18-min-grub-2/</guid><description>GRUB 2 Todays topic was GRUB and bootloader. Of course I won&amp;rsquo;t get to much into the deep, but just to read some of the explanations at least help me to understand it more.
What is GRUB? It stands for Grand Unified Bootloader and the current major version is 2.
Bootloader What is a bootloader? It&amp;rsquo;s basically a program that loads the operating system. After the BIOS make it&amp;rsquo;s system checks the hard drives are red and the first part of the hard drive stores the bootloader.</description></item><item><title>01 - 18 min - Server Configuration</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-18-min-server-configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:08:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-18-min-server-configuration/</guid><description>18 min per Day What are the Rules? Every Day - 18 minutes - for one year.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how far this can get. In the meantime I will try to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
Either just small updates or more content for topics I find interesting.
Server configuration I have two big books about server configuration. One is for linux and one for Windows. I will start with the linux book.</description></item><item><title>03 - Hacking Lab - Scanning the network</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/03-hacking-lab-scanning-the-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:11:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/03-hacking-lab-scanning-the-network/</guid><description>Scanning the network Note: Before going into the fun stuff. Good news! I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed the internet connection problem, by using IP addresses that can communicate. Somehow 192.168.2.1 and 192.168.25.1 can&amp;rsquo;t communicate, even if I&amp;rsquo;m using 255.255.0.0 as a subnet mask. That means that the network is really big now. If you would like to learn more about networking and subnetting, leave me a comment :)
Update the VMs To have fun with the fun stuff, I want to add some configurations to my domain controller.</description></item><item><title>02 - Hacking Lab - Installing the Vms</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-hacking-lab-installing-the-vms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 22:11:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/02-hacking-lab-installing-the-vms/</guid><description>Installation Installing Promox was quite easy. Download, copy with balenaEtcher and boot from the flash drive. Click, Click, Click, Done.
Following the mini plan I&amp;rsquo;ve made, I&amp;rsquo;m starting with the installation of the VMs. Downloading Windows for Evaluation. I need Windows Server 2022, which will run the Domain Controller. And for every Workstation I will use Windows 11 Enterprise, since it&amp;rsquo;s also available for Evaluation in the Evaluation Center.
The first problem occured: I can&amp;rsquo;t start the freshly created machines, because something with Virtualization and my mainboard needs to be configured.</description></item><item><title>01 - Hacking Lab - The idea</title><link>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-hacking-lab-the-idea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:51:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://myl3z.me/posts/01-hacking-lab-the-idea/</guid><description>Welcome Hi! Hello! Welcome!
My name is xander and I like cyber security, software development and servers.
This blog will be my personal blog about cyber security, software development and servers.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see!
Leave me a comment if you have questions or just want to say hi.
First project: Hacking Lab What is a hacking lab?
It&amp;rsquo;s basically a playground for my cyber security stuff. To get a better understand I want to build my own infrastructure and then attack it.</description></item></channel></rss>